FEDERICO BELOTTI

 $(+39)3496508679 \Leftrightarrow belo.fede@outlook.com \Leftrightarrow f.belotti8@campus.unimib.it$

EDUCATION

Università degli studi di Milano-Bicocca

October 2018 - Present

Master in Computer Science

Department of Informatics, Systems and Communication (DISCo)

Università degli studi di Milano-Bicocca

September 2015 - July 2018

Bachelor in Computer Science, 110/110 with honors

Department of Informatics, Systems and Communication (DISCo)

PUBLICATIONS

1. M. Buzzelli, F. Belotti, and R. Schettini, "Recognition of edible vegetables and fruits for smart home appliances," 2018 IEEE 8th International Conference on Consumer Electronics - Berlin (ICCE-Berlin), pp. 1–4, 2018

CARRIER OBJECTIVE

Learn, learn and most importantly: learn!

PROJECTS (https://github.com/belerico)

Insertion matcher UNIMIB

Deep learning framework for product matching task

We have developed a PyTorch deep learning framework to classify couples of products as match or not match, achieving 86% F1-score on the WDC Gold Standard.

Sbarbasearch UNIMIB

Tweets search engine with personalized search

A tweets search engine with personalized search developed in Python with ElasticSearch as a wrapper to Lucene engine. The personalized search has been implemented with a particular type of distributional word embeddings.

SPQRisiko UNIMIB

SPQRisiko board game modeled with intelligent agents

Python multi-strategy SPQRisiko, a famous and tremendously strategic board game, modeled with intelligent agents.

Let's Card UNIMIB

Struts2 webapp with Java Hibernate ORM integration

In a paper-consumerist world, we have develop a simple web application (portable to any device) that lets a regular customer to save his/her promotions in a digital manner.

Bach chorals UNIMIB

Python framework to learn, and generate, Bach chorales with Hidden Markov Models and its generalization.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Programming & Skills
Software & Tools

Python, Java, Matlab, R, MySQL PyTorch, Keras, Docker, Elasticsearch

WORK EXPERIENCE

UNIMIB

March 2019 - February 2020

Researcher

Design and implement semantic matching techniques and show their effectiveness on data relating to descriptions of products managed on eCommerce sites. The semantic matching techniques developed are based on the latest developments in this research area and, in particular, use machine learning methods based on deep neural networks. The activity is located inside of the EW-Shopp technological innovation project, funded in the context of the H2020 program, which includes other European research organizations and companies.

UNIMIB - Imaging and Vision Laboratory

February 2018 - July 2018

Internship

Develop a state of the art method to recognize fruits and vegetables using Convolutional Neural Networks, that results in my bachelor thesis: "Recognition of edible vegetables and fruits for smarthome appliances".

PERSONAL TRAITS

Love beers

Love math (be careful, it does not mean that I always understand her)

Love cinema, music and arts (same as above)

Love sports: swimming and kick boxing

ABOUT ME

I'm a 26 years old student from Bergamo, Italy; I'm currently attending the 2nd year of master in Computer Science at the University of Milano-Bicocca. If you're wondering on why I haven't already finished my student career, the answer is: experience! In fact, when I was 17 years old I left high school (I was studying computer science) to go to work as dishwasher at first, and as bricklayer then. After one year a lot I've learned, mostly about life and hard work, and after some courage gathering I've decided to go back studying computer science at a night school, always working during the day. Year after year, three in total, I've got graduated and I was wondering if I could push me even further, so I decided to try the university career and after almost four years, here I am now. In my free time I love reading novels of the most varied genres, from Tolkien and Ursula Le Guin to Orwell and Dickens and Baricco and many others; I love cinema and arts, even if most of the time I can't really understand paintings, but they are personal and I like them for that; I do kickboxing for sport and I love swimming; last but not least I do really love dancing techno and electronic music: for me, they're therapeutic.